I am about to start another War yep no
no not the turf war it's a completely
different war and it's to do with the
barge you see in my quest to make as
many diamonds as possible I've
introduced logs to my shop now I haven't
got much stock and I've got a slightly
better deal than what Ren is offering
why this is a big deal
is because I'm going in direct
competition
with Ren doll who is actually on the
mycelium team so this is not gonna go
well but it is an important part of the
barge as I continue to upgrade it but
since we're here I also want to point
out that people have signed up to the
barge Quest and I didn't even tell
anyone it's right it's not ready it's
genuinely not ready it's gonna be ready
within the next few hours because I'm
still working on it I but like look
I put some chests down here and I think
people thought that it was ready to go
and we've already got our four people
look look at this
200 diamonds 200 diamonds and a fish 200
diamonds and 200 diamonds and another
fish unbelievable we've got one whole
thousand diamonds ready for the barge
Quest so we are gonna play that later on
because I still need time to finish it
off however what it is time for is a
meeting oh don't we love meetings yes we
do yes we do at the mycelium resistance
headquarters if you missed the last
episode we built this one where'd it go
oh land on the wrong thing it buzzes
here I built the wonderful mycelium
headquarters and we also built this
giant beam of light signaling the goat
and the goat and now it's time to have a
meeting with the resistance and
hopefully with Doc as well and we can
get our act together and do something
about it so let's go how do I get in is
it one of these buttons
oh my goodness it is but
I
I don't think that's the address
but I'm gonna use it can we appreciate
how smooth that was I landed on the
chair okay we
foreign
welcome mycelium resistance members to
the new and improved resistance
headquarters what do we think it's
amazing it's amazing it's lovely it's
all about good to be above ground it is
a fresh air and Welcome to our newest
member doc who has gone full Batman on
us yes
we put a big signal in the sky so you
know I think we asked for that
yeah kind of wait what am I overdressed
or what's the point yeah a little bit a
little bit a little bit overdressed okay
right here's the plan everyone as
everyone knows our base has been lost
and in control by Hep we are now going
on the offensive everyone is going to
have to retaliate in the biggest
offensive that we can muster everyone
except doc doc it is your job we've
called you in so that you can make this
the worst possible place to be if you
are a hep member can you do it
[Music]
[Laughter]
yeah good I hope okay well I I'm scared
of my own base now
we'll leave that in your capable hands
uh I know that I know that Ren you've
got a plan and then the impulse has got
a plan
you've got your game face on yeah
we're coming prepared okay
so now is the time for us to go on the
offensive so get your get your plans
together and the Hep won't know what's
coming unless the audience tell them
which they probably will Oh and before
we take off everybody we got a little
addition to the base if you flip up your
trap door in front of you oh bubbles
ome meeting button is back oh yeah you
got an ender pearl
okay oh
does it
nice I'm
um ether this is kind of awkward but I I
don't have a ball you guys
[Laughter]
um
budget cuts yeah we also cut out the
Note Blocks oh yeah those might reappear
later excellent very nice amazing the
emergency meeting ban is the best
feature of our base in general it's so
cool and I'm probably gonna annoy
everyone with it by pressing
and remember everybody it's about the
principal it is about the right so wait
what do you ever forget just look up oh
dude I I didn't even see that
beautiful only three exclamations though
because we had budget cuts okay budget
cuts
good job good job
so I think that went pretty well and it
looks like doc has already made a start
I don't actually know what he's doing
but he's got a load of stuff here and
there's some Redstone underneath the
island which definitely wasn't here
before I don't know what his plans are
but I yeah look there's I don't want to
know I don't want to know I don't want
to know let it be a surprise shall we so
now it has actually been a few days
since that meeting and the barge Quest
is officially complete all eight stages
of it are ready so let's dive into the
barge get everyone together and let's go
welcome contestants to the very first
and ultimate barge Quest has everyone
kind of read the the rules we'll kind of
know roughly what's happening vaguely I
think so we don't get to go until you
say go that is right yeah so okay I need
you to split into two teams and it's up
to you what team you wanna you wanna I
mean it's clearly happened you want to
be on my team how did that work out that
way
I'm not going to be anywhere near those
pantolines money I'm I'm going on over
here okay so impulse and ren I want you
to go over to the very handsome green on
the right there and B-Dubs and Scar I
want you to go over to the other green
so what I'm gonna have to ask you to do
is when we begin oh wow B-Dubs oh my
goodness speed does put on something no
sure oh wow no service I'm ready for
battle is that just under your shirt
this whole time yes oh okay when we
begin I'm gonna need you to go into
separate calls because you are going to
both in the Box have a different clue
that's going to lead you in different
directions you are not necessarily
following the same pathway the goal of
course is to get to the end of the
treasure hunt where you will get a
fantastic prize worth way more than you
paid to enter and a mega Ultimate Prize
a mega Ultimate Prize and you will also
have to work out between you who gets
what so
are we kind of ready right does it all
make sense I can't give you much more
hint than that I have no idea what we're
doing but yeah okay follow the clues
complete the tasks win the game first
one there wins it is possible to die but
it's unlikely you'll lose stuff but I'm
also here to help out and to kind of
save stuff with this isn't about like
losing gear or anything it's about using
your brain using your Minecraft skills
uh-oh
okay so I'm gonna be watching you guys
on the cam account anything goes wrong
you let me know are we ready
in three
two
one
go go go go go go go go go
he may have wait Diamond Armor what what
do we do open the chest there's a clue
we gotta go on a different call too yeah
okay that was the most expensive stuff
the proper instructions okay they've now
split up into their various calls
they're looking at their first clue and
they're trying to work it out now I need
them both to leave as soon as possible
because my job oh wow they they have
they've figured that out very quickly I
need to put this in here because this
this is important later they're they're
gonna have to come back here there we go
missed clue right now we're mostly going
to watch
from the sides but occasionally I'm
getting involved elsewhere I need to get
my character to the next checkpoint for
them while they're working out their
next clue okay yep it's gonna come here
let's check what B-Dubs and Scar are
doing okay they're in the correct place
so the clue was the brightest shot from
cheapest to most expensive and there's
enough here to get together
some coordinates where did I put the
other one there it is there it is so
that if they put those together they get
coordinates let's check on impulse they
have also found the correct place the
their clue was the two-faced shop inside
and out so the outside has a face
and the inside has a face drumbot you're
doing me proud I'm proud of you look how
cute he is okay right so they are both
working out their coordinates I wonder
if they're gonna fly here instead of
using the nether
so a lot of this treasure hunt comes
down to speed how fast can you travel
across the hermitcraft map really
important okay I'm here oh
both here at the same time okay your
next task is really funny I'm here too
is that okay yeah yeah that's fine
you're both here you've both solved it
very quickly I might add right you may
have crashed in the jungle your your
task is very simple I need help fill up
the chest with stuff I need help mining
this out this is the task go and your
reward will be a map this task is called
friendship help me help me mind this out
I will accept no unfinished Stacks it
has to all be 64. 64 in each one I need
a chest full because I need help digging
this whole thing out so the fact that
scar hasn't made it is terrible B-Dubs
he's gonna trust me I know the Fool's
forgotic Rockets
I left my inner chest when I had to pay
for him oh no all right let's see it is
definitely it is definitely red and
impulse in the lead at the moment
I was in a single man
you have got the very first map you may
now leave this Channel and take the map
and proceed on with the quest amazing
how much more do we need don't lose your
lead guys you're not you're not
far behind we did it we did it
oh a stone stone oh no irritate get that
out of there there we go no no no no no
no no no no no no
there we go the map is yours good luck
with the next stage of the quest that
was like that was a troll that was an
absolute troll that wasn't a real real
part of the quest I just thought I'd add
it in there for fun so right need to uh
wait here for the next one you remember
this from last episode this is the
puzzle box
so good luck to them let's see where
they are scar is at the correct place in
wren's base but he is going the wrong
way because it is right over here just
under this in fact you might be able to
see it
yeah there it is here's the chest and in
this chest is their next clue let's see
where the other team is because this one
was actually slightly more difficult oh
they may have already found it because
they're their clue was in here it was
actually in the bathroom there it was x
marks the spot on the airplane they are
going back already that means Scar and
B-Dubs oh man they're really struggling
ah yeah there we go I think scar has
found it you are ahead you are ahead
right enter all you gotta do all right
there's no instruction go inside the
puzzle box and figure it out get to the
other side this is your one here okay go
inside the puzzle box and get to the
other side check obviously okay no
cheating all right let's see if while
we're waiting for Skyrim B-Dubs they are
falling way behind they need to solve
this room
the two words that make up the best
shopping district Spruce and dark oak
this is dangerous because they can get
stuck oh they might come on figure it
out
oh there we go
there we go they've opened the first
door important not to get stuck very
important not to get stuck
my advice is don't both go in there
and we're still waiting for B-Dubs and
Scar oh they can't quite figure it out
they need to use their bow and arrow to
activate those two buttons
there they are they have just arrived
hello hello very quickly it's very easy
to get stuck so be careful all you gotta
do is get to the other side no cheating
obviously okay you are second place
we know thank you for reminding us we
appreciate that I hate them okay let's
go right we got the two contestants in
each one now oh they have managed to get
through the main door
and now it's their time
to hit the crystals
meanwhile we got B-Dubs and Scar who
have just started the puzzle can they
hit it oh boom they hit it
boom and the Redstone signal goes and
there they go but where's the Jukebox
they need to play the message but how
right let's check on B-Dubs and Scar
they've got through the first one
excuse me Mr Green
yeah I might be stuck in a room with a
lever
well Brett your teammate can get you out
so uh my partner he he shot some
crystals yeah
um and that didn't let me out either no
is there more to the puzzle the same way
you got in there you can get out you
just got to use your Minecraft knowledge
same way I got in oh okay bye
I I kind of like the fact that they got
stuck because now it means that Scar and
B-Dubs can catch up
let's see if they can nail these shots
[Music]
one
four close
two
three
and the door is open but where is the
Jukebox oh they are neck and neck right
now now it is a job to find a jukebox as
soon as possible they're running around
like headless chickens to play the
message there we go oh hello insert team
name here how are you doing I'm guessing
you want your next clue you just did a
whole bunch of stuff right well yeah I'm
gonna give you your next thing but I
think I'm gonna waste a little bit of
your time first because I want to drag
this out as long as possible so I bet
you're pretty stressed right stressed
from all of the the puzzles and the
things that you just did and stuff so
here's what I wanted to do I'm gonna I'm
going to bang the gong for you right so
I want everyone to just take a chill
pill I know this is a race I know that
there's a lot going on this very moment
and I know all you really want is your
next clue
but guess what you're not gonna get it
because I want you to take a deep breath
are you ready and three two one take a
deep breath in
and out
ah
doesn't that feel better
oh your next Clue's at the barge you
just just go back to the barge you know
the box that you put your name on just
go back there the clues the clue was in
there the whole time all right they've
got it they know where they need to go
go back to them they are neck and neck
they are neck and neck so they've got to
now travel back to the barge as soon as
possible off they go in fact we need to
go to our next location as well man this
is this is working I thought something
would have gone wrong by now
they all have decided to fly every
single time these guys keep flying
everywhere instead of taking the nether
one of them could have pulled ahead if
they had all just taken the nether there
is not a lot of tactical maneuvering
going on it oh Ren has made it straight
there and he's found a missed clue and
Scar is very close to the barge now
oh man this is too close to call so
insert team name here oh no he didn't
listen now he's got to listen to the
whole thing again a bunch of stuff right
well yeah oh scar no oh just open it up
just open it up there you go you don't
need to listen to The Clue because I
want to drag this out as long there we
go he's reading it
I've been stressed right right stressed
from all of them now I made this jukebox
intentionally long in case they didn't
listen and they'll have to listen to it
again right there we go so impulse and
ren are firmly on their way to the
coordinates which is where we're waiting
right now for them so this next
challenge is one that you didn't really
know about because I haven't shown it
this is a Riptide Trident course and
what they've got to do
is get themselves through the holes and
over to the other side they can't just
walk around that's you know cheating so
let's see what they've got there they
are there they are
overshooting a little bit who is that
that is Rendog is the first to arrive
oh dear oh dear this is a skill based
challenge now and impulse is here as
well
they've caught up
they have caught up oh my goodness you
guys are naked you literally just
arrived okay your next challenge
everyone is to get to the other side no
cheating I've got a list of instructions
right in front of you there's a chest
each and one totem of undying so make
sure you reset your spawn just in case
you suck at this minigame oh boy oh
great all right remove elytra set spawn
John keep armor oh we should probably go
back in our own costs no Electra this
one no way light truck okay okay right
let's watch this happen
ran is Ren is taking the shot
and he's up they're through who's
struggling back there it's B-Dubs right
this isn't oh
very close to death there oh look at
that Scott oh oh
yeah B-Dubs he made it
and up up
there we go
and he's in B-Dubs is in the lead come
on B-Dubs you got this whoop
nice nice nice nice nice
and up
boom B-Dubs is the first to get there
meaning he wins the lodestone compass
I'm just reminding them that both
players must reach the top so he has to
wait for scar this is a team game and
they've both got to do it oh and ren is
has made it oh impulse is trying to
cheese it by taking the uh the ice pool
I promise you the best way to do this is
to just go back and do it all over again
this is rough oh go on Scott go on Scott
no he didn't make it and ren has made it
to the top okay so now it is a race
between Scar and impulse they have both
got to make it to the top and they've
figured out that you've got to play by
my design and you've got to hit oh no
scar impulse is starting from the start
which I probably should have specified
you don't have to do
where did Scar go there he goes the jump
the jump oh he can't make it
okay they made it onto here
and
I already made it impulse made it and
scar
all you have to do is walk forward oh
they both made it
okay it's kisses so close
oh my goodness I didn't imagine for a
second that this would end up being this
close right go go go go go go go go go
go all they gotta do is follow the
compass
oh wait I better go as well I'm not
meant to be here so the compass
takes you about a thousand blocks I hope
they don't follow me I mean they're they
I mean they probably know where they're
going better than I do actually because
they've got a compass that takes them
directly there all right so that was the
last challenge now it's time for the
finale
the finale is so important okay this is
going to be absolutely manic I don't
know how this is gonna go and we're
about to find out right they may want to
take uh their bed there oh they're back
had a technical glitch with the Redstone
because there was snow underneath but
here we go the finale
first to get a weather Star wins
here we go
hey
oh oh I'm in the crossfire I'm gonna
watch from afar tell you what I'm
actually gonna fly back to the barge
where it's nice and safe
because that's where they've got to go
after they get a Nether Star
oh scar was hit by the Wither right how
we do doing they have got
impulse has died everyone is dying
this is Mayhem
oh my goodness this has been the most
complicated thing ever
there is an aerial battle going on here
Ren Rendog is fighting this Wither in
the air oh and he's doing the most
damage he's got him into the second
phase but remember B-Dubs and Scar can
steal this star there's nothing saying
that they can't I this cabbage Quest is
so much closer than I thought it would
be meanwhile I need to get myself back
to the barge right the first person to
get their nether star back to the barge
wins the game let's see how they're
doing there is a constant very very
painful fight going on oh impulses
withered away what's going on with scar
scar is still floating around has he
lost all his stuff I guess I didn't put
I didn't expect the weather fight to be
this difficult I did think that with
four people it would be fairly easy but
three Withers might be one two two many
but Ren is playing it the right way
taking it in the air where the Wither
can't handle it and just
gliding through and slicing it up oh it
looks like Ren is about to get the final
shot on his with a one more oh there it
goes there it goes it looks like Ren and
impulse are gonna take the win
if Scar and B-Dubs don't pick up the
pace
oh oh Nelly
Dora is here the star is here
the star is right here the star is on
the floor Ren has found a star are they
equally had a chance renner's got it but
I think his stuff is gone
I think I think all his items exploded I
I'm gonna be talking to the camera boy
here but uh
I'll be honest I didn't realize the the
stuff just exploded when you fight with
us that was rough look that he exploded
and then all his stuff exploded
I don't know how that works
Ren and ren has the star but no way to
get it back to the barge
beat us beat ups has his stuff scars
lost his stuff and impulse has also lost
his stuff no no impulse are still going
hilariously Ren died to the Wither when
he had the star on him and it looks like
scar and B-Dubs they stole the star from
Ren
they are on their way back
they are on their way back to the barge
any second now I think this is all over
what a twist
oh man
it looks like this is kind of what I
expected with the withers I just didn't
know that stuff blew up so I'm gonna
have to replace that impulse is still
gonna try and fight the Wither look at
that Majestic man you get him impulse
second place rightfully earned meanwhile
scar is about to take the win very very
soon so we need to prepare ourselves for
the welcome party there we go the winner
is here
I can't believe it I cannot believe it I
can't believe I did it that is that you
I can't believe it you you guys sucked
but you did fantastic it was all
strategy yeah that's what he said
somewhere wherever he is did I get this
right that Ren found the star because I
saw him pick it up he then dived to a
Wither and then you picked it up and
running they did all the fighting and
died like three more times but
eventually got it in the woods sometimes
everything within the first minute like
the withered destroyed all my gear I
know I'm sorry your your stuff is
insured and we will get that sorted
don't worry oh I didn't know that
weather's blew up stuff I thought they
just blew up people and I will now
announce the winner which is
somehow thank you thank you somehow it's
good time for Scar and double O they
literally stole it from you fair and
square stop thieves excuse me gentlemen
disqualified listen Brent diggity dog
does all the hard work does the killing
of the Wither and
look at me I come out of this with
nothing I was watching I was watching he
could have gone down picked up the star
and left but you did it you stuck around
ah and died like again like it was
literally just stand sitting there and
I'm like you know what that is not a
snowball with you know yellow snow
that's a shiny star so I'm gonna also
say that all of your items are insured
for this barge Quest so if anyone lost
stuff I will replace your armor and
tools free of charge I did like quite a
bit of durability on my
elytraction for me I am I lost
everything yeah I I will I'll sort you
out so the last thing to do
is to reveal the grand prize so the
winners take your first plunge yeah
excuse me excuse me
oh there we go oh sweet baby jelly yeah
oh the die bar do you see the die box
and
see you also get it you also get a
pretty good Friday oh thanks thanks a
lot okay there's also a second place
prize here behind the bars okay okay oh
excellent too bad I don't ever pick
extra break sweet also I want to point
out just before you get too excited if
there is some blocks that you guys want
to exchange you can exchange boxes so
for example I know there's like there's
quite a few boxes of redstone maybe
impulse wants to swap them for some
blocks you know whatever you want to do
if you want to do some exchanging it's
up up for grabs the best boxes are on
these end rods
that was super awesome that's good
carefully worth the diamonds I was
awesome yeah I had such a great time it
took an hour we are an hour in because
yeah it was an insurance I'd be angry
there wasn't insurance I didn't realize
where this was gonna blow up everyone's
stuff
yeah guys we could start a shop called
barge 2.0 with all this stuff
what do you think that's genius I will
take all of these boxes back right now
young men okay
now good question does the winners get
the big G yes stop trying to steal
everything in the barge
well speaking of G's GG yeah
I deserve it and you know what you you
get to win with that Rambo outfit B-Dubs
I mean it's beautiful oh for sure thank
you thank you so much my mom made it for
me
she's very talented thank you that was
absolutely insane wasn't it and I kind
of have to preemptively tell everyone
just outright no one broke any rules I
was the one that actually did a bunch of
stuff wrong in that
um for example destroying two
contestants items
but no one broke the rules they won fair
and square I actually figured that
someone would kill the Wither and the
other team may actually steal the start
so it was always intended for that to be
a possibility and they did it they
they stole the star and they got it back
to the barge those were the rules so in
my eyes the whole thing was fair and
square and very close now I do need to
know how did it go it was very very
difficult for me to film and organize
that thing at the same time I was like
I was participating but I also wasn't so
my point of view probably won't be as
entertaining as the other guys so I
can't wait to see their videos of how
that all went down and how much Panic
they were doing so we did actually
we did destroy some items of our friends
so having said that I have produced a
insurance box meaning all of the books
that they're gonna need all of the items
they're going to need so this one's for
scar this one is for Ren Ren told me he
likes his enchants in a specific order
so I've just done my best got some got
lots of books rockets and he said that
he lost some diamonds as well so we're
gonna go drop this off at rendog's base
where it belongs and now no harm no foul
but here's the funny thing I think I
made a loss I have definitely made a
loss I may have gained a thousand
diamonds but I had to spend
about about 500 diamonds worth of
netherrite to get their stuff back okay
so if you take into account all of the
grinding I had to do I'm definitely out
of pocket so next time I do this if I
ever do this at all it depends on if you
guys liked it or not please let me know
I will make sure that it's not possible
to ever lose your items ever
I'll give them diamond armor that
doesn't matter if it gets destroyed
right there we go
rendogs insured items so with all that
said with our big loss and our friends
having a great time in our mini game the
items have been insured and returned to
their owners
and that is all from me so thank you
very much for watching I'd love to hear
your thoughts on this experience it was
very different and I can't wait to see
what everyone else's point of view
looked like because I'm I bet it was
very funny from their point of view
right so thank you very much for
watching and I shall see you in the next
episode goodbye
bye
goodbye